茶室
我以为这个时候我已经会习惯了死亡
I thought I'd be used to death by now.
八条命跟在大冰封中死去的七十亿人比起来
What's eight lives against the seven billion
算得了什么
we lost in the Freeze?
但这样不同
But it's different this way.
这不是因为严寒
This isn't the Cold.
是因为我们
This is us.
人
People.
互相残暴
Wasting each other to violence.
停不下来
And we can't stop.
这是我们对一切的答案
It's our answer for everything.
我们迷失在其中
We get lost in it.
我迷失在其中
I got lost in it.
但现在
But now...
我只想要这一切能停下
All I want is for it to stop.
我只想要有一个我能闭上双眼
I want just one night where I close my eyes
不害怕另一边的夜晚
and I'm not afraid of what's on the other side.
一个我不感到孤单的夜晚
One night where I don't feel so alone...
在雪国列车上  1034节车厢
On Snowpiercer, 1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第七集
"解答一切"
儿子
My son.
主在绝望之时会守护我们
The Lord is watching over us in times of despair.
损失在所难免
Loss comes.
威尔福德知道怎么攻击我们
Wilford knew exactly how to hit us.
他在这边肯定有内应
He has to have someone over here.
一个告诉了他这边紧张局势的人
Someone who told him about the tensions.
人们会责怪车尾
People are gonna blame the Tail.
我得弥补这事
I have to make this right.
我们都需要
We both do.
你证明不是车尾干的
You prove it wasn't the Tail.
与此同时我会防止事态失控
I'll keep a lid on things while you do.
大爱丽丝边境封锁
Big Alice border is on lockdown.
我在每个连接处都派了司闸员
I've got Brakemen on every link.
目前没有问题
There's no trouble yet.
迟早会有的
It's just a matter of time.
是啊  这事会发酵的
Yeah. This is gonna boil.
司闸员博斯科维奇
Breachman Boscovic.
你的损失也是雪国列车的损失
Your loss is all of Snowpiercer's.
你知道是谁干的
You know who did this.
我向你保证不是车尾
I promise you, it wasn't the Tail.
请你远离他们  立刻
Please get away from them. Now.
走吧
Go.
交给我吧
Leave this with me.
拿着  是圣克里斯多福
Here. It's Saint Christopher.
可以保护你
For protection.
我会帮你看着他
I'll keep an eye on him for you.
我保证
I promise.
他忙完这边后  我会带他去茶室
When he's finished here, I'll take him to the Tea Room.
谢谢你  牧师
Thank you, Pastor.
你不能这样涂抹
Hey! You can't smear it like that.
这是蛇形运动  拜托
It's a snaking motion. Come on.
血还多着呢
There's a lot more blood where that came from.
警探
Detective.
要处理的案子好多啊
Wow, what a caseload.
我需要你的帮助
Could use your help.
是车尾人干的
The Tailies did it.
就算不是
And even if they didn't,
像以前那样嫁祸给他们就行
just pin it on them like you used to.
别烦她  她度过了艰难的一晚
Oi. Give her a break. She had a rough night.
你需要什么
What do you need?
我在那边的地板上发现了这个
I found this over there on the floor.
复古威尔福德
It's vintage Wilford.
老式字样的W
Old style W.
你有见过吗
You ever see one before?
或许在头等厢里
Maybe up in First?
没有
No.
你根本没看
You didn't even look at it.
还是没见过
Oh. Still no.
算了
Forget it.
我认识一个或许能帮上忙的人
I know someone who might be able to help.
谁
Who?
一个叫卡佳的女人
This woman, Katya.
她有一个卧铺包厢  里面全是古董
She has a couchette full of vintage stuff.
带我去吗
Wanna take me?
好
Okay.
她当时跟他站在一起
She was standing right there with him.
在边境对面
Across the border.
我听不清  但看上去
I couldn't hear much, but it looked like
他像是在给她一个选择
he was offering her a choice.
她选择留下
She chose to stay.
看上去是这样
That's what it looked like.
但我不知道她的动机
But I cannot know her motives.
派奥德丽过去本身就有风险
It was a risk sending Audrey over there.
她是过去替你执行任务的  不是吗
Well, she was there on a mission for you, wasn't she?
-她完成了吗  -没有
- Did she complete it? - No.
我们还是没法监听到他们的通讯
We still don't have access to their comms.
也许她只是留在那完成任务
So maybe she just stayed behind to finish the job.
不管怎样  她是奥德丽小姐
Well, either way, she's Miss Audrey,
夜车地位最高的女性
Doyenne of the Nightcar.
她是我们的一员
She's one of us.
看上去就是变节  即使真相并非如此
Looks like a defection even if it isn't.
*太阳为何...*
* Why does the sun... *
大爱丽丝  大爱丽丝
Big Alice, Big Alice.
雪国列车致以问候  请回复
Good day from Snowpiercer. Come in...
*海水为何匆匆拍向海岸*
* Why does the sea rush to shore? *
大爱丽丝  雪国列车呼叫大爱丽丝  请回复
Big Alice, Big Alice. Snowpiercer calling. Come in.
快接听  大爱丽丝
Pick up, Big Alice.
我知道你在听  你这个变态的臭老头
I know you're listening, you psychotic old goat.
你好  本  你好像很需要人关注
Hello, Ben. You sound needy.
我们今晚将到达喜马拉雅山环形路
We're going to be hitting the Himalaya Roundabout tonight.
大事件啊
Big event.
我们要回去接你们勇敢的首领  梅兰妮
We're turning back for your brave chief, Melanie.
我们想和奥德丽说话
We want to speak with Audrey.
瞧谁又去我的火车头了
Ah, look who's in my Engine again.
奥德丽
Audrey!
是莱顿大王
It's King Layton.
来接听
Collect.
她在泡澡
She's been in the tub.
心情不太好
Bit of a mood.
昨晚那些响声是怎么回事
What was all that noise last night?
警报声  边境封锁
Alarms, sealed borders.
遇到麻烦了吗
Some kind of trouble?
我们列车上有些骚乱而已
Just a little domestic unrest.
但你肯定对此毫不知情  对吧
But you wouldn't know anything about that, right?
稍等  先生们
One sec, gentlemen.
她来了  迷人但怒气冲冲
Here she comes, fetching but grumpy.
你好  莱顿  我来了
Hello, Layton. I'm here.
你错过了宵禁
You missed curfew.
我这人一向有点叛逆
Well, uh, I've always been a bit of a rebel.
你还好吗
You all right?
他想知道我是否强迫你留在这里
He wants to know if I'm holding you against your will.
我没事
I'm fine.
如果你想  我们准备好打开边境门  让你回来了
We're ready to open the border for you if you want.
先不要
Not yet.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
这还不够好
Not good enough.
她是在铤而走险
She's walking the line.
或者她刚被睡完  正在玫瑰水里泡澡
Or she's freshly shagged, bathing in rosewater.
我们必须假设她的身份暴露了
We have to assume that she's been compromised.
没错
Yeah. We do.
你有没有听到关于雪国列车的消息
Have you heard anything about Snowpiercer?
警报响了一整晚  没人知道发生了什么
The alarms went off all night. No one knows what's happening.
威尔福德把自己和奥德丽锁在车头里
Wilford has locked himself in the Engine with Audrey,
我被拒之门外
and I have been shut out.
有人受到伤害了吗
Has anyone...been hurt?
你的澳大利亚人一定没事
I'm sure that your Aussie is fine.
他们要袭击我们吗
Are they going to attack us?
艾莉克斯  我们该担心吗
Alex. Should we be worried?
我去弄清楚怎么回事
I'm gonna find out what's happening.
等等
Wait!
赛克斯
Sykes.
等一下
Wait a minute.
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
是我们干的  对吗
This was us, right?
如果威尔福德没告诉你
If Wilford didn't tell you,
那你就无权知道
then you're not supposed to know.
为什么
Why not?
我不知道
I don't know.
你去问他
Take it up with him.
三等厢的情况越来越糟
It's getting bad in Third.
他们都认为是我们杀了维修工
They all think we killed the Breachman.
反正我们待在这里很安全
Yeah, well, we're safe back here.
我们可以关上这边的门
We can close our own doors.
我们在前车的同伴怎么办
What about all our people uptrain?
莱茨和温妮
Lights and Winnie.
是啊
Yeah, right.
你的英语能力逐渐恢复了  大力士
See, your English is coming back, Strong Boy.
你说了"和"这个词
You used the word "and."
莱茨和温妮今早去了市场部署
Lights and Winnie set up in the Market this morning.
我们分布在各车厢
We're spread out all over,
但我们的人需要回来这里
but our people need to be back here.
抱歉  但我得回去工作了
I'm sorry, but I have to get back to work.
-放心  我们没事的  -好
- It's all good. We cool. - Okay.
兄弟们  你们有什么想法
Well, boys, what you reckon?
我们得去前车把所有人带回来
Well, we've gotta go uptrain and get everyone.
确保他们平安回家
Make sure they get back home safe.
对
Yeah.
但他不能去
But not him.
他太引人注意了
He sticks out like a sore thumb.
大力士可以留在这
Strong Boy can hold it down back here.
和
And.
那派克呢
What about Pike?
派克是怎么了
What is it with Pike, man?
你不想知道的
Ah, you don't wanna know.
我想只有你和我了
I think just you and me, mate.
我们一会去车尾集合
Hey, we're gonna gather back in the Tail.
是你
You.
我们
We, uh...
我们不想惹麻烦
we don't want any trouble.
你杀了我的朋友
You killed my friends!
现在轮到我杀你了
And now, I kill you!
别让他出来
Don't let him back out.
我们一开始就不该
We shouldn't have left the pastor
让牧师看着他
to watch over him in the first place.
萨姆
Sam.
你有多担心
How worried are you?
每次你叫我名字时我都很担心
I'm always worried when you start using my first name.
你在想什么
What's on your mind?
昨晚奥德丽和威尔福德先生
When Audrey and Mr. Wilford turned back
在边境回头时
at the border last night...
他让我去大爱丽丝
He asked me to step over onto Big Alice.
但你还在这里
Hey, you're still here.
我不知道该怎么办
Didn't know what to do.
曾经的我一定会过去
There was a time that I would have.
现在你不确定了
Now you're not so sure.
我效忠雪国列车  和你一样
I serve Snowpiercer, just like you.
有七年时间我们曾井然有序
We had order for seven years.
我知道下令的是梅兰妮
I know it was Melanie,
但那些是他的规矩  不是吗
but they were his rules, weren't they?
是的  我们曾经井然有序
Yes, we had order.
你还想干那种工作吗
You want to do that job again?
冻掉他人的手臂
Taking arms?
在车后侧管理集中营
Running a gulag at the back of the train?
走吧
Come on.
为什么都交给你了
So why's it all on you?
莱顿已经够忙的了
Oh, Layton has enough to deal with.
这些人那么怪罪车尾人
All these people pointing fingers at Tailies,
按说他会想对此做点什么
you'd think he'd want to do something about it.
他有的
He is.
他交给我  去搞定这事
Trusting me to, uh, you know, get it done.
而我...
And I...
你想证明自己
You want to prove yourself.
八个维修队的人  都在同一时间被谋杀
Eight Breachmen, all murdered at the same time.
那就是八个愿意为威尔福德杀人的人
That's eight people willing to kill for Wilford.
威尔福德无形的手
Ah, the invisible hand of Wilford.
这是真的  相信我
Oh, it exists, believe me.
他在这安排了人幕后操纵
He's got someone here pulling the strings.
进来  进来
Eh, hey, come, come.
下午好
Good afternoon.
她不说英语
Uh--she don't speak English.
她想知道你们在找什么
Sh--she want to know what you look for.
衣服  帽子
Clothes? Hat?
你告诉我
You tell me.
她说扣子是夹克上的
She say button come from jacket.
怎么有这么多威尔福德的东西
What's with all this Wilford stuff, anyway?
祖母认识威尔福德先生很久了
Grandmother know Mr. Wilford for long time.
她以前在谢菲尔德是他邻居
She was neighbor in Sheffield.
待他如自己侄子  她说
Like a nephew, she says.
她带他去公园  教堂
She take him to park, to chapel.
她说他喜欢教堂
She say he love chapel.
他会在玻璃窗里点亮红色的蜡烛
He light red candle in glass window.
这些红色小灯笼就是这个意思  对吗
Oh, is that what all these little red lanterns are about, then?
祖母让我每天都点  当作守夜
Grandmother ask me to light each day as vigil
直到威尔福德先生回来
until Mr. Wilford return.
我们也会给顾客
We give them to customer.
他们也替他点亮
They light it for him also.
这衣服所有扣子都在
All the buttons are here.
这是一套衣服中的一件吗
Is this part of a set?
对
Da.
没错  姊妹夹克
Ah, yes, sister jacket.
祖母上周换掉了
Grandmother trade last week.
换了个毛绒帽子
For fur hat.
你还记得她和谁换了吗
Do you remember who she traded with?
一个美丽的女人
Oh, beautiful woman.
光鲜得像头等厢乘客
Fancy like First Class.
很高
Very tall.
雪国列车的公民
Citizens of Snowpiercer.
今天我们为维修队的人默哀
Today, we are all in mourning for our Breachmen.
我们害怕
We are afraid...
因为我们中有人想要我们害怕
because there are those among us who want us to be.
这次暴力是精心策划用来离间我们的
This violence was orchestrated to divide us.
-让我们受损  -是车尾
- To compromise us... - It was the Tail!
通过除掉我们中最优秀的人
By taking out our best.
我们不能反目成仇
We can't start turning on each other.
否则就正中了他们的下怀
That's exactly what they want to happen.
无论是谁犯下这可怕的罪行
Whoever did this terrible crime
他们想让你们认为始作俑者是我们中的弱者
wants you to believe that it was the weakest among us.
胡说
Bullshit!
莱顿以前就是车尾人
Layton was a Tailie!
真正的敌人在大爱丽丝上
The real enemy is back there on Big Alice,
伺机静候
lying in wait.
你们的有些邻居支持他回归
Some of your neighbors support his return,
但我们已经摒弃了《威尔福德法》
but we cast away Wilford Law once already.
我提醒各位团结大家的信念
And I will remind you of the call that unites us.
我们列车一心
We are one train.
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
我们为之奋斗的不是这个
This is not what we fought for.
我不确定他们会以你想要的方式去理解
I'm not sure they'll take that the way you want them to.
我必须要为车尾辩护
I had to defend the Tail.
他们现在还没有发声的途径
They don't have a voice right now.
把威尔福德先生牵扯进来
Bringing Mr. Wilford into it,
你这是要他们站边
you're asking them to pick sides.
他必须要做点什么
He had to do something.
那么  请务必  继续吧
Well, then, by all means, carry on.
她也许是对的
She might be right, you know.
我们都知道这只是刚刚开始
We both know this is just the beginning.
我留下来了
I stayed.
这不是你想要的吗
Isn't that what you wanted?
我想要你在我身边  奥德丽
I want you with me, Audrey.
真心的在我身边
Really with me.
我没法一个人做这事
I can't do it alone.
那么  就像我相信你一样相信我
Well, then trust me like I'm trusting you.
我想我应该得清楚我陷入了什么样的处境
I think I should know what I've gotten myself into.
你想要摊开了说话
You want all our cards on the table?
是的
Yes.
我在你洗澡的时候
I found this screwdriver in your things
在你的衣物里发现了这个螺丝刀
while you were taking a bath.
你要告诉我这是干什么用的吗
You want to tell me what it's for?
我想你知道那是干什么用的
I think you know what it's for.
对调通讯线
Swap the comm lines
这样雪国列车就可以监听我的火车头
so Snowpiercer can listen in on my Engine?
你这么做了吗
Did you do it?
没有
No.
你留下来
Did you stay here
是为了完成你那个小任务吗
so you could complete your little mission?
不是
No.
我留下来
I stayed...
是因为我感受到了一股引力
because I feel a pull.
就在这里
Right here.
但是经过你对我所做的一切...
But after everything you've done to me...
我不明白这种感觉
I don't understand it.
但是我仍在这里
But I'm still here.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
穿好衣服
Get dressed.
我想让你见个人
There's someone I want you to meet.
-我们要去哪  -你会知道的
- Where are we going? - Oh, you'll see.
你必须要证明自己
You're going to have to prove yourself,
和其他人一样
like everyone else.
约瑟夫  这是怎么回事
Joseph, what's going on?
我队伍里的这个可怜人
You see, this poor, poor member of my crew
已经完全崩溃了
has gone all to pieces.
他需要你的帮助
He needs your help.
不  不要
No. No!
不  快走开
No, no! Leave me alone!
别管我  不  快走开
Leave me alone! No! Leave me alone!
快走开  别管我
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
不
No!
不要
请别这样
Please, no!
这位是凯文
This is Kevin.
-不  -我要你治好他
- No! - I need you to fix him.
莱顿的革命本应该是为了我们所有人
Layton's revolution was supposed to be for all of us!
去他妈的
To hell with him!
一朝车尾人  永远都是车尾人
Once a Tailie, always a Tailie!
这是威尔福德的列车
This is Wilford's train!
以前一直是  以后永远也是
Always was, always will be.
我们去干掉几个车尾人吧  走吧
Let's get some Tailies! Come on!
天呐  莱顿现在是骑虎难下了
Oh, man, Layton's in for it now.
派克  你还好吧
Pike? You good?
莱顿
Layton.
我的老哥
My man.
我很好
I'm good.
你确定吗
You sure?
你看上去
'Cause you don't, uh...
看上去不太好
you don't look so good.
特伦斯那事并没有如计划那般  但是...
Thing with Terence didn't quite go as planned, but...
我很欣慰  现在你欠我人情
I take comfort in knowing that you now owe me.
没错  有我为你撑腰呢
Yeah, hey. I got your back.
你为什么不现在回到车尾呢  好吗
Now, um, why don't you head back to the Tail, okay?
-外面很危险  -没事
- It's dangerous out here. - Nah.
我没事
I'm good.
你现在是个靶子
You're a target.
我这个样子没人能认出来  莱顿
Nobody recognizes me like this, Layton.
真的吗
Really?
我查了总账
I-I checked the ledger.
计算了数字
I did the figures.
我证实了
And I have proven...
现在  天平其实
that the scale is actually
更偏向派克一点
now a little more in Pike's favor.
我计算了你欠的债
I counted your debt.
你现在已经被标记了
You are now marked.
这边  这边  低调点
Oh, hey, hey. It's this way. This way. Lay low.
他还好吗
Is he okay?
我想我让他有了心理创伤
I think I messed him up.
来  你可以扭转局面的
Come on. You can turn this around.
你在这呢
There you are.
你去哪了
Where were you?
奥德丽在帮我做点事
Audrey's helping me with something.
做什么事
With what?
一个小项目
Little project.
到时你就知道了
You'll see.
你又瞒着我
You're shutting me out again.
我好奇是为什么
I wonder why that is.
因为与其像你承诺的那样去占领雪国列车
'Cause instead of taking Snowpiercer like you promised,
你更愿意和你的贱人一起乱搞
you would rather just mess around with your whore.
我真的很喜欢你的大胆  艾莉克斯
I do love your nerve, Alex.
但你不必把事情放在心上
But you don't want to make this... personal.
以前你什么事都告诉我
You used to tell me everything.
你以前还感激我为你所做的每一件事
And you used to appreciate everything I've done for you.
但后来你把梅兰妮带来
But then you let Melanie in.
偷偷带她进兵舍
Took her into the barracks in secret.
没错  这事我知道
Yes, I knew about that.
我想你们已经抱过了吧
I expect you had some lovely hugs.
我不该在你和梅兰妮之间做选择
I shouldn't have to choose between you and Melanie.
但你必须要做  必须要选择
But you do. You do have to choose.
你和她在一起待了一周
You spend one week with her...
就忘了我救过你
And you forget that I saved you.
每一天你都应该感谢我
You should be thanking me every day
把你从严寒中救回来
for rescuing you from the Cold.
你在这个地球上呼吸的每一天
Every day you breathe on this Earth
都是我给你的
is a day I gave you.
所以如果你想参与我的计划
So if you want to be part of my plans...
你就必须要提醒我
You're gonna have to remind me...
为什么我带上了你
Why I brought you along.
没事了
It's okay.
没必要觉得丢人
There's no reason to be ashamed.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
凯文
Kevin.
Kevin!
我一直看到他在浴缸里
I just keep seeing him in the bathtub.
他带你去洗澡吗
He took you to the bath?
他一定非常喜欢你
He must really like you.
不
No...
我明白他的...
I understand his...
他的喜欢一开始会让人感到困惑
his affection can be confusing at first.
但你难道不想摆脱这种伤痛吗
But don't you want to be rid of this pain?
我能看看吗
Can I see?
愈合得很好
It's healing nicely.
太可怕了
It was horrible.
我知道
I know.
我知道  但你就快好了
I know. But you're almost there.
你看
Look.
天呐
My God.
我们俩都做了同样的选择
We both made the same choice.
都是因为爱他
Out of love for him.
不不
No, no...
-他救了你  -不
- He saved you. - No!
不  他毁了我
No, he broke me.
-不  他救了你  -不
- No, he saved you. - No!
他救了你
He saved you.
你只是害怕而已
You're just afraid.
没人会像他这样爱你
No one's ever loved you like him.
没人会的
No one else would.
你想再成为他的人对吗
You want to be his again, don't you?
遇到威尔福德之前  你什么也不是
You were nothing until Wilford.
-他给了你一切  -不
- He gave you everything. - No.
-帮帮我  不  -你...
- Please help. No! - Just--
-闭嘴  -别说了
- shut up! - Stop!
闭嘴
Shut up!
你必须要再深入一点  凯文
You're gonna have to go deeper, Kevin.
更深入  更黑暗
Deeper and darker.
这是我的专长
This is what I do.
我帮人找回他们失去的情感
I help people reconnect with what they've lost.
天呐
God.
我要你放手
I need you to let go.
我要你冷静一点
I need you to calm down.
屈服吧
Just give in.
这是在干什么
Well, what's all this?
我找到了一样东西
I found something.
在一起谋杀现场附近
Near one of the murders.
看着眼熟吗
Look familiar?
是威尔福德古董  非常稀有
It's vintage Wilford. Rare piece.
我从来没见过这个东西
I've never seen it before.
是吗
Yeah?
我擅自翻了你的东西
Took the liberty of going through your things.
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind.
肯定是从什么地方掉出来的
Well, it must have fallen off somewhere.
我可不这么认为
Yeah, I don't think so.
女维修工绮莉力气很大
Cherry the Breachwoman was strong.
过来
Come here.
她还手了是吗
She fought back, didn't she?
你替威尔福德杀了她
You killed her for Wilford.
这边谁说了算  是你吗
So who's over here calling the shots? Is it you?
你陷得太深了  警探
Oh, you're in so deep... Detective.
你连眼前的事物都看不到
You can't even see what's in front of you.
你觉得你很聪明
You think you're so smart,
但你总是慢半拍
but you're always two steps behind.
这辆列车需要改变
This train needs change.
一个新的牧人
A new shepherd.
革命现在已经开始
And the revolution is starting. Right now.
-带走她  -走吧
- Take her away. - Let's go.
做好准备  亲爱的
Buckle up, sweetheart.
快  进来
Quick! In here!
市场上也有问题
There's trouble in the Market too.
很快整辆列车都会出现问题
It's gonna be the whole train soon enough.
露丝
Ruth...
我们得走了
We have to move!
你们要去哪
Where do you think you're going?!
快进来
Quick. In here.
快  快  快
Come on. Come on, come on, come on!
-只是乘客服务部  -我们走吧
- Just Hospitality. - Let's go.
这里什么情况
What's going on here?
我们被困住了  跟你一样
We're trapped. Same as you.
扎拉  给特里斯坦打电话
Zarah, call Tristan.
跟她说我们需要护送
Tell him we're gonna need an escort.
嗯
Right.
看看这里都有谁
Let's see who we have here, then, shall we?
怎么了
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
莱茨
Lights?
温妮在车尾见过她
Winnie remembers her from the Tail.
我几乎都不去车尾
I was hardly ever in the Tail.
你试图要她的胳膊
You tried to take her arm.
就在不久前
It wasn't that long ago.
结果你选择了她妈妈的   记得吗
You took her mother's arm instead. Remember?
苏珊
Suzanne?
嗯  她死了
Yeah. She died.
死于断臂导致的并发症
Of complications from the de-arming.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
她哥哥呢
Where's her brother?
他在革命中牺牲了
He died fighting in the revolution.
她只剩我了
I'm all she has left.
露丝
Ruth?
-特里斯坦  特里斯坦  -露丝
- Tristan? Tristan! - Ruth?
露丝
Ruth!
-你找到护卫了吗  -没有
- Oh! Have you got the escort? - No.
出了点状况
Uh, there's a bit of a situation.
针对车尾人的暴力
Targeted violence against Tailies.
到处都在发生袭击
Outbreaks popping up all over the place.
车尾人在外面不安全
Tailies aren't safe out here.
没事  没事
It's all right, it's all right.
冷静  给我点时间
Stay calm. Just give me a second.
那小女孩呢
Where's that little girl?
-温妮  我的天
- Winnie? - My God.
-她肯定溜出去了  -莱茨
- She must have slipped out. - Lights--
-去找她  -不不不
- Gotta find her! - No, no, no, no!
你不能出去  不  我去  我去
You can't go out there. No. No. I'll go. I'll go.
扎拉  现在你负责
Zarah, you're in charge.
别让任何人进出这道门
Don't you let anyone through this door.
好
Okay.
小温妮  你在这做什么
Little Winnie, dude, what are you doing here?
很危险
It's dangerous.
怎么了
What? What is it?
那个是车尾人
That one's a Tailie!
我认识他
I know him!
-抓住他  -你想要什么
- Grab him! - What do you want?
不不不  退后
No, no, no, no. Hey. Get back!
放开我  放开我
Let me go! Let me go!
放开我
Let me go!
不  我不想死
No! I don't wanna die!
放开我
Let me go!
放开我  放开我
Let me go! Let me go!
放开我
Let go of me!
快走
Let's go!
不  放开我
No! Let me go!
闭嘴
Shut up!
我不想闭嘴
I don't wanna shut up!
慢点
Slow down.
"他们的牧人把他们引入歧途"
"Their shepherds have led them astray."
他昨天对我引用了这句话
He quoted it to me yesterday.
我真笨
I'm such an idiot.
头等厢的那婊子甚至戴着圣克里斯多福的挂坠
First Class bitch was even wearing Saint Christopher.
-再给我看下  -好
- Look, just--just give it to me one more time. - Okay.
今早我看到罗根牧师
I saw Pastor Logan give Boki
给波吉同样的项链垂饰
that same medallion this morning.
跟他给我的那个一样
Exactly like the one he gave me.
你觉得他是故意放波吉走的吗
You think he let Boki out on purpose?
让一让
On your left.
等等  怎么了
Hold on. What's going on?
有组织的威尔福德匪徒不断出现
Organized Wilford mobs keep popping up.
到处都在发生暴乱
There are riots all over the place.
他们在后车甚至挟持了一个车尾人
They've even taken a Tailie hostage downtrain.
快去  这边交给我
Go, go! I got this.
我自己能应付
I can handle it on my own.
祝你好运
Good luck.
温妮
Winnie?
坚强点  小温妮
Be strong, Winnipeg.
我爱你
I love you.
温妮
Winnie?
Winnie!
你在这儿呢
Ah, there you are!
我在车上到处找你
I've been looking all over the train for you!
你是怎么到这上面来的
How'd you get all the way up here?
你不用怕我  温妮
Look, you don't have to be scared of me, Winnie.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
你得跟我走  我好带你回去
You have to come with me so I can take you back--
带你回去见你朋友
To take you back to your friends.
你妈妈
Your mum...
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mum.
我小时候我也失去了妈妈
Do you know I lost my mum too when I was little.
我把她从你身边带走很残忍
It was cruel what I did, taking her away from you.
我以为我是在做正确的事
I thought that I was doing the right thing.
我是在按规章办事
I was following the rules.
但那不是对的  是吗
But that wasn't right, was it?
是错的
It was wrong.
大错特错
It was very, very wrong.
我真希望能时光倒流  问你
I wish I could take it back, Winnie.
我真的希望
I wish that I could.
我
I...
我在躲坏人
I'm hiding from the bad men.
我知道
I know.
你很聪明
You're very clever.
如果你跟我来
I can keep you safe from them
我能保护你不受他们的伤害
if you come with me.
你能跟我走吗
Will you come with me?
来吧  宝贝
Come on, sweetheart.
快来
Come on.
知道你愿为他做任何事
Knowing you would do anything for him
是世界上最美好的感觉
is the most wonderful feeling in the world.
那种忠诚
That loyalty...
那种忠诚  是解脱
that loyalty, it's relief.
很少有人能理解这种爱
It's a love very few people understand.
他是唯一一个理解你的人
He's the only one who ever understood you.
你在遇到威尔福德之前一无是处
You were no one until Wilford.
你欠他一切
You owe him everything.
我欠他一切
I owe him everything.
谢谢你  威尔福德先生
"Thank you, Mr. Wilford."
Thank you, Mr. Wilford.
好了  凯文
All right, Kevin.
站起来
Stand up now.
来
Come.
你看上去  容光焕发
You look...reinvigorated.
搞定了吗
All done?
凯文
Kevin.
给威尔福德先生下跪
Kneel for Mr. Wilford.
舔威尔福德先生的拖鞋
Now lick Mr. Wilford's slipper.
你能回来真好
It's nice to have you back.
谢谢
Thank you.
不  不
No! No!
不
No!
不  不
No! Ah! No!
-不  不要冻我的手  -闭嘴
- No! Not my arm! - Shut it!
你们不必这么做
You don't have to do this.
-我们可以做交易  -让他闭嘴
- We can make a deal. - Shut him up!
他们回来了
They're back.
进去吧
There you go.
-谢谢  -安德烈
- Thank you. - Andre!
你去哪  怎么了
Where are you going? What's going on?
他们在后车挟持了一个我们的人
Ah, they've got one of us downtrain.
-车尾人  -是的
- A Tailie? - Yeah.
我要跟你去
I'm coming with you.
拜托  能让我跟着你吗
Please, can I just come with you?
好的  走吧
All right. Let's go.
贝丝
Bess!
请坐
Have a seat.
你之前在跟谁说话
Who were you talking to?
还能有谁
Who else?
你在祷告
You were praying.
当然
Of course.
在这样的日子里  我最需要祂的指引
Times like these are when I need his guidance the most.
今早波吉怎么了
What happened with Boki this morning?
在我走后
After I left?
我给了他一些空间
I...gave him some space.
去哀悼
To grieve.
出什么事了吗
Something wrong?
那都是在演戏吗
Is it all an act?
什么意思
What do you mean?
茶杯
The teacup.
灵性
The spirituality.
都是扯淡  对吗
It's all bullshit, right?
你在给威尔福德卖命
You're the one working for Wilford.
-别管  -贝丝
- Leave it. - Bess.
别骗我
Don't lie to me.
我从没骗过你
I never lied to you.
你只是没准备好倾听
You just weren't ready to listen.
这么久以来你一直在利用我
Were you just using me all this time?
你内心的怒火  我也能感觉到
That rage inside of you, I feel it too.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
你渴望能抓住什么
You were so desperate for something to hold onto.
相信什么
Something to believe in.
我想帮你
I wanted to help you.
你杀了八个人
You killed eight people.
这是换取和平的一个小代价而已
A small price to pay for peace.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
不  不
No! No!
-不  -放他走
- No! - Let him go!
-放他走  -我们不要再听你的了
- Let him go! - We are done listening to you!
等等  杰克斯
Wait--Jakes.
杰克斯  我认识你  你为什么要这么做
Jakes, I know you. Why are you doing this?
-我们一起抗争过  -那是个错误
- We--we fought together! - That was a mistake.
就不该让你离开车尾的
Never should've let you out of the Tail.
-叛徒  叛徒  -嘿  嘿
- Traitors! Traitors! - Hey, hey, hey!
够了  够了
Hey, stop it! Stop it!
你要想惩罚谁的话  拿走我的手臂
You wanna punish somebody, take my arm.
拿走我的手臂  放掉派克
Take my arm. Let Pike go.
-他疯了  -不可能
- Hey, he's crazy, man. - No. No way, man.
-不不  -嘿  嘿
- No, no. No! - Hey! Hey!
你们想要的是我  对吗
I am the one you want, right?
-你们恨的人是我  -安德烈
- I'm the one you hate. - Andre...
我夺走了你们的一切
I took everything that you had,
然后我给了我朋友
and I gave it to my friends, right?
所以带走我  拿走我的手臂
So take me. Here. Arm me.
来啊
Come on.
不  不
No! No! Hey!
不
No!
不  不
No, no...
不  等等
No! Wait!
住手  住手
Stop it! Stop!
这太野蛮了
This is barbaric!
这人是你们的领袖
This man is your leader!
你们选择了他
You chose him!
你们想要别人来领导
You want someone else in charge,
那就号召改变
then call for change.
但别因为你们可以
But don't strip him down and mutilate him
就剥下他衣服  让他残废
just because you can.
这样不对
It's not right.
相信我  我了解的  我这么做过
Believe me, I know. I've done it.
你们再也变回不了曾经的样子
You'll never be the same again once you have.
这不是办法
This is not the way!
不再是了
Not anymore.
-拜托  -司闸员要来了
- Please. - The Brakemen are coming!
我们得走了
We gotta go!
这事没完
This ain't over.
滚吧
Yeah, piss off!
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
快点  快点
Come on, hurry up!
你注意点  派克
Watch yourself, Pike.
我们都想要稳定
We all crave stability.
但威尔福德能带来秩序
But Wilford brings order.
我们必须受苦一小会儿
We just have to suffer for a moment...
才能得到救赎
to get to our salvation.
没有伤害你就找不到解脱
You can't find relief without...hurting.
动手吧
Do it.
我不会杀了你
I am not going to kill you.
你要是死了  就没人知道真相了
If you die, no one learns the truth.
我向你祈祷
I pray to you.
我向你祈祷  我汲取力量
I pray to you, and I draw strength.
欢庆
Rejoice.
不  不
No! No!
爸爸
Daddy!
我错过了螺丝锥吗
Did I miss the corkscrew?
没有  过来坐
No. Come sit.
他们在选边  艾莉克斯
They're choosing sides, Alex.
跟我来
Come with me.
那是什么意思
What does it mean?
他们在召唤你  约瑟夫
They're calling for you, Joseph.
列车想要威尔福德
The train wants Wilford.
我们要点燃一根吗
Should we light one?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
安德烈
Andre?
叫海德伍德夫妇准备冷淡鲍勃
Tell the Headwoods to prep Icy Bob.
是时候了
It's time.